Shiyang Jiang

SUMMARY

Motivated master graduate of Archiving and Preservation with 3 years of studying and working experience in US university archives and museums. Excels at database management and moving image archiving. Has strong communication, English – Chinese translation, and problem-solving skills.

EDUCATION

New York University, MA, Moving Image Archiving and Preservation	09/2019 - 05/2021
Xiamen University, BFA, Theatre, Film, Television and Literature	09/2015 – 06/2019
Lund University, Exchange Studies, Film Studies	01/2018 - 06/2018

WORK EXPERIENCE

Media Ecology Project, Dartmouth College, Remote Work

07/2021 - 06/2022

Metadata Archivist

- Created workflows for organizing metadata records (XML and CSV) for two research projects funded by NEH
- Cleaned up, hosted and shared metadata across the collections via Airtable database
- Extracted extract technical metadata from video files via bash and Python script

The Flaherty, New York, US

07/2021 - 12/2021

Archivist

- Conducted collection assessment of archival holdings (analog & digital), inventory, and preliminary inspection
- · Organized a community archiving workshop, trained volunteers to rehouse unprocessed materials
- Provided reference service for researchers and enhanced inquiry form for request

NYU Cinema Studies Archives, New York, US

09/2019 - 05/2021

Archive Assistant

- Inspected, repaired, and catalogued 16mm archival prints from collection
- Scanned film via MWA Flashscan and used DustBuster to clean digitized films, updated via Filemaker Pro

International Film Festival & Film Restoration Forum, Xiamen, CH

04/2019 - 07/2019

Assistant

- Organized the premiere screenings of restored classic films, renting venue, attaining authorization, tracking international shipping of DCPs and writing promotion materials
- Communicated with guests and translated conference manual, introduced the Archive Center and XMU, making sure the event goes smoothly

SKILLS

Language: native Chinese, fluent English (IELTS 7.5) **Working skills:**

- information management system (ArchivesSpace, Filemaker Pro, Airtable)
- metadata organization (Dublin Core, PBCore, Open Refine)
- AV handling and digitization (16mm, 35mm, VHS, MiniDV, DAT, Betacam),
- preservation (familiarity with vrecord, ffmpeg, BigIt)
- simple programming (Bash and Python for AV preservation, XML)
- video editing (Adobe Premiere Pro)

Other: event organization, Chinese-English translation, Microsoft applications (Word, Excel)

INTERNSHIPS

Smithsonian Institute's Center for Folklife and Cultural Heritage, Remote Work Collection Care Intern

07/2021 - 09/2021

- Researched best practices for preserving DVD contents, transcoded videos using FFmpeg, ingested data into SI Digital Asset Management System
- Cleanup metadata for recordings of Folklife Festival, updated finding aid records via ArchivesSpace
- Created guide for archiving streaming programs

Metropolitan New York Library Council, New York, NY

01/2020 - 05/2020

Archive Intern

- Created preservation masters and access copies for the VHS, Betacam SP, DAT, and MiniDV tapes of Art and Science Collaboration, Inc. (ASCI) symposia recordings using Vrecord and FFmpeg
- Developed and implemented web archiving workflows to three ASCI websites using webrecorder.io

Xiamen University Film Archive Studies Center, Xiamen, China

07/2018 - 07/2019

Film Archive Intern

- Inspected and repaired 35mm films from collection.
- Assisted in guest tours, conferences, and panels hosted by the Center

ARCHIVAL PROJECTS

The Film-makers' Cooperative, Spring 2020

- Assessed the condition of the 16mm circulation film collection and completed an assessment report **WNET Thirteen**, Fall 2019
- Conducted copyright research of TV Episode Creative Person: King Vidor (1965)

APEX Robert Flaherty Farm Project, Fall 2019

- \bullet Began collection assessment, inventoried, and rehoused boxes of photos, films, and documents **Home Movie Day NYC,** Fall 2019 & 2020
- Inspected and prepared home movies brought by the participants, introducing films to the audience

ACADEMIA

Society of Cinema and Media Studies Conference, "Organizing Metadata: Digital Humanities Necessity", 2022 **Pordenone Silent Film Festival**, Collegium member, 2020

MIAP Thesis: History, Technology, and Preservation of Biograph Company Mutoscope Reels, 2019

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Xining FIRST International Film Festival, 2018

- Synchronized live soft-titles for foreign film screenings and moderated Q&As
 Pixel Skane Film Festival, 2018
- Official photographer for festival winners

AWARDS

New York University, Academic Excellence Award & Robert Sklar Memorial Scholarship, 2021

NYU Cinema Studies Department, Merit-based Scholarship, and Internship Scholarship, 2019 – 2021

Xiamen University, Academic Excellence Scholarship, 2018 - 2019